You will now hear a conversation between a university professor and a student about the essential characteristics and differentiating features of a literary review.
First, you have some time to look at questions 21 to 25.
Now, listen to the first part of the conversation and answer questions 21 to 25.
Hello. Good morning, Anna. How are you and how is that literary review coming along? Are you still working on it?
Hello, sir. I'm doing okay. Thank you for asking. Yes, I'm still working on it and that's why I'm here. I'd like to talk to you about it.
I'm drawing a blank on how to get started. I was, um, well, maybe you could suggest something to get me going.
Certainly. You do know that you must write a literary review. Have you ever written one and do you have any idea on how you plan to go about it?
Well, I know it's a literary review, but I don't really know what it really is or how to go about it.
I've written one before. I would imagine that, well, you take a book such as a novel or a book of poetry, settle into an easy chair and then read it.
Once you've finished it, you either give it thumbs up or thumbs down. Isn't that how a literary review is done, right?
Actually, no, that's not how it's done and that's just too simple. Also, that doesn't really mean anything.
If you really like a book or dislike it, you should be able to state why you like or dislike it.
You might also find that there are parts of a book that you like, but overall you might dislike it and vice versa.
Now, the nature of a literature review refers to any collection of materials on a particular topic and not necessarily the great literary texts of the world.
Now, what am I talking about here? Literature in and of itself could be anything from a set of government pamphlets on the colonial methods of the British in Africa
to scholarly articles on the treatment of a torn ligament. It could also entail fiction, prose or anything in between.
Furthermore, when you write a review, it does not mean that your reader wants you to give your personal opinion on whether or not you like the book or text.
Before you hear the rest of the conversation, you have some time to look at questions 26 to 30.
Now listen to the second part of the discussion and answer questions 26 to 30.
So what is a literary review?
A literature review discusses published information in a particular subject area and sometimes information of a particular subject area within a certain time period.
A literature review can be just a simple summary of the source, but it usually has an organizational pattern and combines both summary and synthesis.
OK, but how is a literature review different from an academic research paper?
The main focus of an academic research paper is to develop a new argument. A research paper will contain a literature review as one of its parts.
In a research paper, you use the literature as a foundation and as support for a new insight that you might contribute.
The focus of a literature review, however, is to summarize and synthesize the arguments and ideas of others without adding your own contributions.
OK, I see. I wonder about the purpose of writing a literature review.
I'm glad you brought that up because it's exactly what I wanted to talk about next.
You see, literature reviews provide you with a handy guide to a particular topic.
If you have limited time to conduct research, literature reviews can give you an overview or act as a stepping stone.
For professionals, there are useful reports that keep them up to date with what is current in their field.
For scholars, the depth and breadth of the literature review emphasizes the credibility of the writer in his or her field.
Literature reviews also provide a solid background for a research paper's investigation.
Comprehensive knowledge of the literature of the field is essential to most research papers.
But I'm just curious about who writes these.
Literature reviews are written occasionally in the humanities, but mostly in the sciences and social sciences.
Within experiments and lab reports, they constitute a section of the paper.
Sometimes a literature review is written as a paper in itself.
Well, I think it is now going to be easier for me to write the review.
Good. But don't forget that you have to submit it by the end of the class on Monday.
I'll be sure to do that. Thank you for your help.
That is the end of Part 3. You now have half a minute to check your answers.
Now turn to Part 4.